<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="anxiety_01_title">Anxiety</string>
    <string name="anxiety_01_body">
        Worry. Apprehension. Fearing the worst. Anxiety is all of these things and more. When you are constantly feeling on edge and worried about something, you are probably suffering from anxiety. Here’s the rundown of what it really is:
        \n<b><font size="14">What is it?</font></b>
        \nAnxiety is a general term that can cover several different types of disorders. All of
        them have nervousness, worry, fear, and apprehension in common. Sometimes the feelings can be overwhelming enough to manifest physical symptoms.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Why does it happen?</font></b>
        \nAnxiety is considered a mental illness. It happens when someone is faced with a situation that overwhelms them. Those who have anxiety disorders might even have difficulty living a normal life.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Is it hereditary?</font></b>
        \nSome studies say that certain individuals are predisposed to anxiety disorders due to their genetic code; however, other studies say there is no hereditary link at all.
        \n\nWhat are the physical symptoms?
        \nThose with anxiety might suffer physical manifestations of their worry, including a
        rapid heartbeat, sweating, problems with sleep, an inability to concentrate, shortness of breath, fidgeting, fatigue, and the like.
        \n\nAnxiety is not stress, though the two terms are often used interchangeably. Stress is
        something that is usually transient and can be remedied; anxiety might be a constant, unrelenting sensation that requires intervention from a professional in order to solve.
    </string>
    <string name="anxiety_01_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS AND
        ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="anxiety_02_title">HOW IS ANXIETY RELATED TO STRESS?</string>
    <string name="anxiety_02_body">
        When it comes to stress, we know exactly where it is coming from: That deadline, the
        decline of a relationship, the argument with the boss at work. Anxiety is much harder to
        pinpoint, and can be a constellation of problems that seem to build up at the same time.
        Then the physical problems begin to set in. According to Melissa Cohen, LCSW, anxiety
        takes on a life of its own. \“We are less aware of what we are anxious about and the
        reaction we have becomes the actual problem,\” she said. \“We get anxious when we keep thinking about the same thing over and over. We develop a sense of uneasiness and since we don\’t want to forget, we fixate. Mild anxiety can actually be a positive experience for some but when it is prolonged and happens in the absence of a stressful event or begins to interfere with normal life, it needs to be addressed.\”
    </string>
    <string name="anxiety_02_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="anxiety_03_title">What Is Anxiety?</string>
    <string name="anxiety_03_body">
        All people are familiar with anxiety, which ranges from a vague apprehension to an intensely uncomfortable feeling similar to fear. Anxiety is a normal part of being human. Anxiety serves an important purpose: It is a warning signal, triggered by a conscious or unconscious perception of danger. It helps us pay attention to something important. Anxiety is experienced both physically and psychologically. Physical symptoms of anxiety include:
        \n<b>•</b>	Muscle tension or trembling
        \n<b>•</b>	Pounding heart
        \n<b>•</b>	Dizziness or light-headedness
        \n<b>•</b>	Sweating, feeling hot or flushed
        \n<b>•</b>	Tightness in chest or throat, breathing difficulties
        \n<b>•</b>	Trouble falling asleep, waking in the night or too early
        \n<b>•</b>	"Butterflies in the stomach"
        \n<b>•</b>	Low appetite, nausea, indigestion
        \n<b>•</b>	"Hypervigilence," feeling \"on edge\"
        \n\nPsychological and cognitive symptoms of anxiety include:
        \n<b>•</b>	Poor concentration or lack of focus, distractibility
        \n<b>•</b>	Excessive worrying or thinking something is going to go wrong
        \n<b>•</b>	Specific fears (e.g., fear of heights, fear of crowds)
        \n<b>•</b>	Self-criticism, self-doubt
        \n<b>•</b>	Trust issues, paranoia
        \nThese symptoms are natural in many situations, and most people have some of these
        symptoms from time to time. However, there is a point at which anxiety may become extreme and interfere with day-to-day living. In such cases, one needs to consider whether an anxiety disorder may be present, requiring some type of treatment.
    </string>
    <string name="anxiety_03_cite">Anxiety Disorders. (2018, November 21). Retrieved from https://caps.ucsc.edu/resources/anxiety-disorders.html?fbclid=IwAR2P8UOCz6oUEP4HQJ2y8Nt_2A2ACugV-HKAZwlUggEh7XdmK_nYINY76v4</string>
    <string name="anxiety_04_title">Anxiety Disorders</string>
    <string name="anxiety_04_body">
        When anxiety is higher than what is typical, is ongoing, and causes problems, it may be considered an anxiety disorder. Anxiety disorders are the most common mental health issue in the United States, affecting up to 18 percent of people each year. However, because some anxiety is normal for all people, it can be difficult to determine when anxiety is a problem. Questions to consider are:
        \n\n<b>•</b>Is this anxiety part of a repeated, ongoing pattern?
        \n<b>•</b>	How much does it get in the way of my life?
        \n\n<i>If a repeated pattern of anxiety increases to the point where it is hard to control
        and interferes with your ability to work or have relationships, you can be said to have
        an anxiety disorder.</i>
        \n\nSince our natural \"warning systems\" are complex, there are many ways in which anxiety
        can show up. Sometimes anxiety is a rare occurrence, triggered only by specific situations. Sometimes it is always present, subtly distracting us and wearing us down. Some common anxiety problems are described in the following sections.
        \n\n<b>Generalized Anxiety Disorder</b>
        \nGeneralized anxiety disorder (GAD) involves higher than usual levels of day-to-day worry and anxiety about a variety of areas, such as school or work, relationships, day-to-day tasks, health, money, and self-image. As the name implies, the anxiety is not focused on one particular thing. The disorder develops gradually and can begin at any point in the life cycle but usually develops between childhood and middle age. Other anxiety disorders, depression, or substance abuse often accompany GAD. GAD can be mild, moderate, or severe, and the level of severity will impact how well the person can function.
        \n\n<b>Phobias</b>
        \nPhobic disorders involve fear of a specific thing or situation (e.g., crowds, enclosed spaces, spiders) and are characterized by fear or discomfort triggered by that thing or situation and avoidance of or distress from the situation that interferes with school, social life, or other important aspects of living. Phobias are very common, affecting 4 to 5 percent of the U.S. population in a given year and up to 11 percent of people in their lifetime.
        \n\n<b>Panic Disorder</b>
        \nPanic disorder involves repeated episodes of panic, which hit suddenly. Symptoms of a
        panic attack include:
        \n\n<b>•</b>Shortness of breath or choking feeling
        \n<b>•</b>Racing heart or chest pain
        \n<b>•</b>Sweating, chills, or hot flashes
        \n<b>•</b>Nausea, dizziness, or shaking
        \n<b>•</b>Fear of dying or going crazy
        \n\nWhile these attacks often come out of the blue at first, they can later be triggered by
        specific circumstances; some people even develop panic about having a panic attack. Increased anxiety around having a panic attack can lead to avoidance of crowds or not going out, which can result in social isolation. Panic disorder affects 1 to 4 percent of the U.S. population.
        \n\n<b>Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</b>
        \nObsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD) involves having either obsessions or compulsions that interfere with your life.
        \n\n<b>•</b>Obsessions are intrusive thoughts or images that recur despite attempts
        to stop them, such as worries about germs or fears that something will happen to a loved one.
        \n<b>•</b>Compulsions are behaviors that are repeated in an attempt to prevent or decrease anxiety. Compulsions are hard to control and interfere with everyday life and/or take up excessive time. Examples are excessive cleaning or hand-washing and needing to check things (e.g., whether you locked the door) multiple times.
        \n\nObsessive-compulsive disorder affects 2 to 3 percent of the population.
        \n\n<b>Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder</b>
        \nPost-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) involves a reaction to experiencing or witnessing an extremely frightening event, such as being assaulted or raped or having a serious accident. People who suffer from PTSD:
        \n\n<b>•</b>Re-experience the event through nightmares or waking "flashbacks"
        \n<b>•</b>Avoid places and situations that are reminders of the event
        \n<b>•</b>May feel emotionally numb or even have partial amnesia as a way of
        psychologically avoiding reliving the experience
        \n<b>•</b>Have symptoms of increased arousal, including being easily startled
        \n<b>•</b>Often have insomnia and poor concentration
    </string>
    <string name="anxiety_04_cite">Anxiety Disorders. (2018, November 21). Retrieved from https://caps.ucsc.edu/resources/anxiety-disorders.html?fbclid=IwAR2P8UOCz6oUEP4HQJ2y8Nt_2A2ACugV-HKAZwlUggEh7XdmK_nYINY76v4</string>
    <string name="anxiety_05_title">Tools for Anxiety Management</string>
    <string name="anxiety_05_body">
         When you are suffering from anxiety, professional help is always recommended. But what you can you do in between visits with your therapist or counselor? What can you do if the anxiety becomes overwhelming? There are ways that you can bring the anxiety back under control. These tips and tools might help.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">KEEP YOURSELF BUSY.</font></b>
        \nOne of the best ways to ease anxiety is to not think about it. How do you do that? By
        staying as busy as you can. The more you are moving and doing things, the less likely you will have time to dwell on what is bothering you.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">TURN TO NATURAL REMEDIES.</font></b>
        \nNatural remedies, such as lavender aromatherapy or chamomile tea, have been proven to
        help relieve stress and anxiety. These natural remedies should always be used properly – ask your doctor if they will be okay to take along with any medications you might be on.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">GET PHYSICAL.</font></b>
        \nWorking out anxiety with a lot of sweat works for some. Hit the gym and hit it hard – the more
        you work out, the more good hormones are released. You might also sleep better, have better digestion, and feel better overall.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">TALK IT OUT.</font></b>
        \nWhen you can’t take one more minute of what is going on inside your head, it’s time to talk to
        someone else. Discuss what is bothering you. If you don’t want to talk to someone at that moment, write it all down on a piece of paper.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">WALK AWAY FROM THINGS THAT BOTHER YOU.</font></b>
        \nDoes watching the news make you anxious? Turn off the television. Does talking to a
        particular person make you feel nervous? Avoid them. Does your chest get tight when you think about that big test? Do what it takes to move your mind to something else.
    </string>
    <string name="anxiety_05_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="anxiety_06_title">>What is it in relation to anxiety and stress?</string>
    <string name="anxiety_06_body">
        Mindfulness has been proven to reduce stress and
        anxiety, and in some cases, actually prevent it from happening in the first place. Not
        only does mindfulness pull you out of your own head and help you see the bigger picture,
        it can reduce physical stressors that might make your mental state feel even worse.
        \n\nBy focusing on the present, you are not dwelling on the mistakes of the past, nor are you overwhelmed by thoughts of the future. You are focused on the here and now, and that can allow your subconscious to work on the things that are bothering you.
    </string>
    <string name="anxiety_06_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="anxiety_07_title">How can you approach mindfulness?</string>
    <string name="anxiety_07_body">
        Starting a routine of mindfulness can be tough, especially when you are entrenched in a fast-paced world. But it is definitely worth a shot.
        \n\nStart by setting aside some time to focus on the here and now. This means choosing a
        quiet spot where you will not be disturbed, and where distractions are at a minimum. Focus on every aspect of your body, one at a time, starting with your breathing. Move up from your toes, focusing in the sensations you feel in every part of yourself, until you reach your head. What thoughts are there? What are you feeling at the moment? Just acknowledge those things, breathe in deep, but do nothing about them. The goal is to live in the moment, not look for solutions.
        \n\nYou can indulge in this during other times as well. For instance, while eating a meal,
        focus strongly on the flavors and textures as they move over your tongue. Focus on your breathing, the smells of the food, the motion of swallowing it. Try to be as deeply in that moment as you can be, and fill up your senses with what you find there.
    </string>
    <string name="anxiety_07_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS AND
        ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="anxiety_08_title">Mindfulness Tips and Techniques</string>
    <string name="anxiety_08_body">
        Ready to try it? These tips can help you get on track.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">MEDITATE.</font></b>
        \nLet your thoughts go where they may, but don’t pay much attention to them. The goal is
        to listen to the quiet inside you.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">LISTEN TO YOUR BODY.</font></b>
        \nWhat is it saying? Focus on the sensations you are feeling, including the stressful ones. Then
        take a deep breath and envision letting them go into the world, outside of you.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">LET THOUGHTS GO.</font></b>
        \nDo the same thing with your thoughts. Acknowledge what comes into your mind (\“yes, I am
        scared\”), and then let it float away while you move on to something else.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">RUN THROUGH THE SENSORY GAMUT.</font></b>
        \nFocus on your body again, and what it feels at every point. Are your feet warm? Is your hand
        tingling? Focus strongly on the sensation, acknowledge it, and then go to another body part. Get in touch with you.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">CLENCH AND RELEASE.</font></b>
        \nStill feel tense? Starting at your toes, clench a body part one at a time. Hold the clench for a
        few seconds. Then slowly release while exhaling. Go up your body, working every muscle group, until you are at the top of your head. Then do it again if you need more relaxation.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">TRY AGAIN.</font></b>
        \nMindfulness can be tough to learn. If you don’t seem to “get it” the first time, keep
        trying.
        Mindfulness is different for everyone, and it will take some time for you to figure out what it means for you.
    </string>
    <string name="anxiety_08_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
</resources>