<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="stress_01_title">What is stress?</string>
    <string name="stress_01_body">Stress is the body’s reaction to a challenge. Though stress is often perceived as bad, it can actually be good in some respects. The right kind of stress can sharpen the mind and reflexes. It might be able to help the body perform better, or help you escape a dangerous situation. Stress produces a physiological reaction in your body. Hormones are released, which results in physical manifestations of stress. These can include slowed digestion, shaking, tunnel vision, accelerated breathing and heart rate, dilation of pupils and flushed skin. This process is often referred to as the “fight or flight” response. That is just what it sounds like: Our bodies are poised to either run away from the stressor or stick around and fight against it.</string>
    <string name="stress_01_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>

    <string name="stress_02_title">Ways of defining stress</string>
    <string name="stress_02_body">
        <b>A stimulus-based definition</b>
\n
The first definition suggests that stress results from pressure. The greater the pressure the more likely that the recipient, whether a person or a load-bearing beam, will succumb. When the (external) stimulus becomes too great, (internal) collapse becomes inevitable. This definition focuses on external sources of stress and encapsulates well its cumulative nature. Adding one more ounce to the weight on the beam may make little difference to the total load but may yet be enough to cause it to break. This is the main definition still provided in the Oxford English Dictionary: \"to subject (a material thing, a bodily organ, a mental faculty) to stress or strain; to overwork, fatigue."
\n\n
        <b>A response-based definition</b>
\n
The second definition focuses on stress as a response to noxious or aversive stimuli. This is the aspect of stress emphasized by Selye (1956), who measured stress in terms of physiological responses, such as those represented by sympathetic adrenal-medullary activity or by pituitary-adrenal-cortical activity. Selye observed what he called the general adaptation syndrome (GAS) during which the physiological response to stress progresses through three stages. First, the body is alerted and responds with an alarm reaction. Next, autonomic activity is triggered as the body prepares to deal with the stress. This is the stage of resistance. Finally, if the stress continues beyond the capacity of the body to respond, the system is damaged and may collapse. This is the stage of exhaustion.
\n
This definition has contributed greatly to the thinking about stress, and it is commonly assumed that psychological responses follow a similar course, although the processes may have an insidious as well as an alarm-based onset. The duration of the stage of resistance, when the person is adapting to, or coping with, the stress depends on specific characteristics of the person suffering the stress, but the assumption is that at some stage, if the stress persists, exhaustion or collapse becomes inevitable.\n
\n\n
        <b>Stress as a dynamic process</b>
\n
Purely stimulus or response-based definitions of stress have thus both contributed to understanding of the phenomenon but they both have limitations. Definitions of stress with more value in clinical practice now emphasize that stress is a dynamic process reflecting both internal and external factors: characteristics of a person and his or her circumstances, as well as the interactionsbetween them. These newer views of stress come from greater understanding of the part played by cognitive factors (thoughts, attitudes, beliefs, images) in psychological well-being. The amount of stress experienced by individuals is determined by the perceived demands upon them as well as by their perceived resources. Cognitive factors thus influence both the stimulus and the response sides of the equation.
\n
Lazarus and Folkman\'s (1984) definition of stress reflects very clearly this way of thinking. They say that stress is "a particular relationship between the person and the environment that is appraised by the person as taxing or exceeding his or her resources and endangering his or her well-being". Two implications of this definition have greatly influenced current thinking about stress and therefore should be made explicit.
\n\n
<b>Implications of a dynamic, cognitive definition of stress</b>
\n
The first implication is that there will be wide differences between people both in the things that are perceived as stressful and in the perception of their ability to respond appropriately. This may mean that the best judge of someone\'s level of stress is the person themselves. An organized, rigid business man may find that adapting to a flexible, unstructured environment taxes his resources to the limit even though his job seems to others not to be particularly demanding. Or conversely someone who regards stress as a psychological weakness to which he or she is invulnerable may misinterpret or ignore signs of stress and need others to point them out. If a housewife with young children supposes that she should be able to respond to each of the small demands made on her (sorting out washing, deciding what to eat, fetching and carrying from school), she will be dismayed to find that an additional task such as taking clothes to the cleaners feels like the last straw. But the appraisals: "nothing I do is particularly difficult" and "anyone should be able to find time for something so trivial" reveal that she may have underestimated the total size of her load, or given insufficient weight to certain types of stressors.
\n
Thinking in terms of appraisals broadens the focus of the clinician. It clarifies how someone who apparently has too little to do may yet feel stressed. An elderly person, or someone who is unemployed, may be subject to few (external) demands but yet have to make demanding internal readjustments. The range of stress stimuli, or possible stressors, is thus greatly expanded. Feelings that cause distress can be stressors as much as the things that provoke them (frustration, jealousy, boredom). The reaction to feeling stressed can provoke more stress, as when someone thinks that showing stress is a sign of failure or weakness. Prolonged, or chronic uncertainty, especially about major life changes, is particularly stressful (threats of redundancy, or the possibility of serious illness), but less so if it is expected and considered (appraised) as normal (waiting for GCSE or A level results).
\n
The second implication of the definition is that stress is determined by the relative balance between two types of appraisal: perceived demands and perceived resources. If the resources outweigh the demands then the person may feel relatively un-taxed. If the person is \'in balance\' then he or she should be operating at maximum eminency. Distress, or suffering, arises when perceived demands outweigh perceived resources. \'Coping\' is the mechanism that potentially provides a degree of control over the balance, and will therefore be considered next.</string>
    <string name="stress_02_cite">Butler, G. (1993, August). Definitions of stress. Retrieved from https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2560943/</string>

    <string name="stress_03_title">Three Types of Stress</string>
    <string name="stress_03_body">
According to the American Psychological Association, there are three types of stress: acute, episodic acute and chronic.
\n\n
        \n<b>Acute stress</b>
\nAcute stress is the most common form and is the result of recent or anticipated stressors. Acute stress can be both positive and negative. For example, the excitement before a fun event is a type of positive acute stress. Getting into a car accident is negative acute stress. As long as the acute stress doesn\’t last for extended periods or occur too frequently, there is nothing wrong with suffering from acute stress. It happens to all of us, and it passes with time.
\n\n
        \n<b>Episodic acute</b>
\nEpisodic acute stress is acute stress that occurs frequently. This is the kind of stress that continuously pops up, sometimes in a pattern. It is accompanied by worry and angst about things that are happening to you or around you. You might be especially prone to this is you have a \”type A\” personality, as you can have a sense of urgency and a need to get things done that might actually become overwhelming. Episodic acute stress is a recurring type of stress, happening over and over.
\n\n
        \n<b>Chronic acute stress</b>
\nChronic acute stress can be thought of as never-ending stress that relentlessly wears away at you. If you don\’t see an end in sight, if you are facing something that has no way out, then you are likely to begin suffering from chronic stress. This type of stress eventually begins to affect your health, and can lead to heart problems, strokes, or even cancer, among other issues. Chronic stress definitely requires reaching out for help.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_03_cite">nCohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>

    <string name="stress_04_title">Causes of Stress</string>
    <string name="stress_04_body">The situations and pressures that cause stress are known as stressors. We usually think of stressors as being negative, such as an exhausting work schedule or a rocky relationship. However, anything that puts high demands on you can be stressful. This includes positive events such as getting married, buying a house, going to college, or receiving a promotion.
\n
Of course, not all stress is caused by external factors. Stress can also be internal or self-generated, when you worry excessively about something that may or may not happen, or have irrational, pessimistic thoughts about life.
\n
Finally, what causes stress depends, at least in part, on your perception of it. Something that\’s stressful to you may not faze someone else; they may even enjoy it. While some of us are terrified of getting up in front of people to perform or speak, for example, others live for the spotlight. Where one person thrives under pressure and performs best in the face of a tight deadline, another will shut down when work demands escalate. And while you may enjoy helping to care for your elderly parents, your siblings may find the demands of caretaking overwhelming and stressful.
\n\n
Common external causes of stress include:
\n &#8226; \tMajor life changes
\n &#8226; \tWork or school
\n &#8226; \tRelationship difficulties
\n &#8226; \tFinancial problems
\n &#8226; \tBeing too busy
\n &#8226; \tChildren and family
\n\n
Common internal causes of stress include:
\n &#8226; \tPessimism
\n &#8226; \tInability to accept uncertainty
\n &#8226; \tRigid thinking, lack of flexibility
\n &#8226; \tNegative self-talk
\n &#8226; \tUnrealistic expectations / perfectionism
\n &#8226; \tAll-or-nothing attitude
\n\n
<b>Top 10 Stressful Life Events</b>
\nAccording to the widely validated Holmes and Rahe Stress Scale, these are the top ten stressful life events for adults that can contribute to illness:
\n1.\tDeath of a spouse
\n2.\tDivorce
\n3.\tMarriage separation
\n4.\tImprisonment
\n5.\tDeath of a close family member
\n6.\tInjury or illness
\n7.\tMarriage
\n8.\tJob loss
\n9.\tMarriage reconciliation
\n10.\tRetirement
    </string>
    <string name="stress_04_cite">Segal, J., Smith, M., Segal, R., and Robinson, L. (November 2018). Stress Symptoms, Signs, and Causes. Retrieved from https://www.helpguide.org/articles/stress/stress-symptoms-signs-and-causes.htm</string>

    <string name="stress_05_title">Symptoms and Signs</string>
    <string name="stress_05_body"><b>Disclaimer</b>
\nThere are four primary types of symptoms of stress: physical, emotional, cognitive and behavioral. Depending on the individual and the cause of the stress, the number of symptoms from each category can vary. The chart below will give an overview to the types of symptoms that may be present in someone suffering from stress.
\n
\n<b>Physical Symptoms</b>
•	\nIrregular bowel movements
•	\nInvoluntary twitching or shaking
•	\nIrregular or missed periods
•	\nGetting sick more often than normal
•	\nReduced libido
•	\nChest pain with or without tachycardia
•	\nHeadaches
•	\nNausea
•	\nMuscle aches
•	\nTrouble sleeping
•	\nHeartburn or indigestion
•	\nFatigue
•	\nFlushed skin
•	\nClenched teeth
•	\nUnusual changes in weight
\n
\n<b>Emotional Symptoms</b>
•	\nLess than normal patience
•	\nFeelings of sadness and/or depression
•	\nFeelings of being overwhelmed
•	\nRestlessness
•	\nReduced or eliminated desire for activities once enjoyed or regularly done
•	\nIrritability
•	\nSense of isolation
•	\nTrouble coping with life\’s issues
•	\nMore frequent or extreme pessimistic attitude
\n
\n<b>Cognitive Symptoms</b>
•	\nImpaired concentration
•	\nTrouble with remembering things, such as homework assignments or deadlines
•	\nChronic worrying
•	\nAnxious thoughts or feelings
•	\nReduced or impaired judgment
•	\nImpaired speech (mumbling or stuttering)
•	\nRepetitive or unwanted thoughts
\n
\n<b>Behavioral Symptoms</b>
•	\nChange in eating habits
•	\nChange in sleeping habits
•	\nNew or increased use of drugs, tobacco or drugs
•	\nNail biting
•	\nPacing
•	\nAbnormal failure or delay to complete everyday responsibilities
•	\nSignificant change in school or work performance
•	\nUnusual desire for social isolation
•	\nFrequent lying
•	\nTrouble getting along with peers, such as coworkers, classmates or teachers
</string>
    <string name="stress_05_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="stress_06_title">Improving your ability to handle stress</string>
    <string name="stress_06_body">
        \n<b><font size="14">GET MOVING.</font></b> Upping your activity level is one
        tactic you can employ right now to help relieve stress and start to feel better.
        Regular exercise can lift your mood and serve as a distraction from worries, allowing you to break out of the cycle of negative thoughts that feed stress.
        Rhythmic exercises such as walking, running, swimming, and dancing are particularly effective, especially if you exercise mindfully (focusing your attention on the physical sensations you experience as you move).
        \n\n<b><font size="14">CONNECT TO OTHERS.</font></b> The simple act of talking face-to-face
        with another human can trigger hormones that relieve stress when you’re feeling agitated
        or insecure. Even just a brief exchange of kind words or a friendly look from another
        human being can help calm and soothe your nervous system.
        So, spend time with people who improve your mood and don’t let your responsibilities keep you from having a social life.
        If you don’t have any close relationships, or your relationships are the source of your stress, make it a priority to build stronger and more satisfying connections.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">ENGAGE YOUR SENSES.</font></b>Another fast way to relieve stress
        is by
        engaging one
        or more of your senses: sight, sound, taste, smell, touch, or movement.
        The key is to find the sensory input that works for you.
        Does listening to an uplifting song make you feel calm? Or smelling ground coffee? Or maybe petting an animal works quickly to make you feel centered? Everyone responds to sensory input a little differently, so experiment to find what works best for you.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">LEARN TO RELAX.</font></b> You can’t completely eliminate stress
        from your
        life, but you can
        control how much it affects you. Relaxation techniques such as yoga, meditation, and deep breathing activate the body’s relaxation response, a state of restfulness that is the polar opposite of the stress response. When practiced regularly, these activities can reduce your everyday stress levels and boost feelings of joy and serenity. They also increase your ability to stay calm and collected under pressure.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">EAT A HEALTHY DIET.</font></b> The food you eat can improve or
        worsen your
        mood and affect your ability to cope with life\’s stressors. Eating a diet full of
        processed and convenience food, refined carbohydrates, and sugary snacks can worsen symptoms of stress, while a diet rich in fresh fruit and vegetables, high-quality protein, and omega-3 fatty acids, can help you better cope with life’s ups and downs.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">GET YOUR REST.</font></b> Feeling tired can increase stress by
        causing
        you to think
        irrationally.At the same time, chronic stress can disrupt your sleep. Whether you’re having trouble falling asleep or staying asleep at night, there are plenty of ways to improve your sleep so you feel less stressed and more productive and emotionally balanced.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_06_cite">Segal, J., Smith, M., Segal, R., and Robinson, L. (November
        2018). Stress Symptoms, Signs, and Causes. Retrieved from https://www.helpguide.org/articles/stress/stress-symptoms-signs-and-causes.htm/</string>
    <string name="stress_07_title">Five School Stress Busting Tips</string>
    <string name="stress_07_body">
        No matter where you are in the school journey,these tips can help you cope with and manage the stress that comes along with it.
        \n<b>GET PLENTY OF SLEEP.</b>
        \nNot getting enough sleep impairs academic performance and makes it harder to get
        through the day.
        \n\n<b>THINK POSITIVE.</b>
        \nResearch has shown that positive thinking may improve physical well-being, produce lower feelings of depression and produce lower levels of distress.
        \n\n<b>HAVE A STRESS \“OUTLET.\”</b>
        \nThis could be a social activity like going out or participating in intramural sports,
        finding a hobby or joining a social club.
        \n\n<b>ENGAGE IN RELAXATION TECHNIQUES.</b>
        \nThis can include things like slowly counting to
        ten, meditation, thinking positive thoughts, visualization or playing with a stress ball.
        \n\n<b>TALK TO SOMEONE.</b>
        \nSometimes just talking about what’s stressful or having someone listen to your problems
        can drastically reduce stress.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_07_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="stress_08_title">Get Help for Student Stress</string>
    <string name="stress_08_body">
        There are several resources available on
        campus to help you deal with students stress. The chart below can help point you in the right direction to find help on your school\’s campus.
        \n<b>Academic Issues</b>
        \nYour academic or student advisor can provide advice or guidance. The on-campus academic services office should be able to arrange a tutor or other extra academic help.
        \n\n<b>Substance Abuse</b>
        \nThe student health center, counseling services center, or campus medical facility will have free and anonymous therapy or counseling services available.
        \n\n<b>Eating and Weight Management</b>
        \nThe student health services and recreation/fitness center might have fitness experts or counselors to help you.
        \n\n<b>Time Management</b>
        \nThe academic services office or student services office can point you in the right direction to more effectively manage your time.
        \n\n<b>Sexual Problems</b>
        \nThe student health center can provide physical checkups and STD/STI screenings, as well as counseling for issues sexually active students may encounter.
        \n\n<b>Depression/Anxiety</b>
        \nIn addition to the student health center, your school may have a counseling and psychiatric services center which can provide mental health services.
        \n\n<b>Health Concerns</b>
        \nStudent health services are always available to answer any health questions you might have.
        \n\n<b>Finances</b>
        \nThe financial aid office and student services center will have information and advice about managing money.
        \n\n<b>Housing Issues</b>
        \nYour resident advisor and student housing department will have procedures in place to deal with problems with roommates or living facilities.
        \n\n<b>Problems Relaxing</b>
        \nMany schools have a massage and/or physical therapy team which can provide services to help students unwind.
        \n\n<b>Homesickness,Family Issues and Bereavement</b>
        \nCounseling will be available in at least one, if not all, of the following organizations: student health services, counseling and psychiatric services center or student services center.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_08_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="stress_09_title">Five Work Stress Busting Tips</string>
    <string name="stress_09_body">
        Every job is going to be stressful at some point. Whether you are working on a tight
        deadline or facing a make-or-break situation, here are a few ways that you can alleviate stress, at least to some extent.
        \n<b>MAKE THE MOST OF WORKDAY BREAKS.</b>
        \nTake some time to cool down and take a deep
        breath. A slow walk and deep breathing during the middle of the day can help center you.
        \n\n<b>HAVE A PLACE TO VENT.</b>
        \nYou might not want to discuss your work troubles
        work coworkers, as gossip can run rampant. But have someone you can talk to outside of work who will understand your situation.
        \n\n<b>WALK AWAY.</b>
        \nNever let yourself become angry and lash out at
        work – that will be detrimental to your work experience and lead to more stress. Find some way to blow off steam.
        \n\n<b>STAY REASONABLE.</b>
        \nThere are certain job standards you must live up
        to, but don’t be pushed to go too far above what is reasonable for your pay grade. Never expect perfection!
        \n\n<b>TWEAK YOUR JOB DESCRIPTION.</b>
        \nIf you find that you are consistently doing work
        that is not in your job description, speak to your employer about either delegating that work to someone else or compensating you fairly for it.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_09_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="stress_10_title">Get Help for Career Stress</string>
    <string name="stress_10_body">
            <b>Employee helpline</b>
        \nMost companies have an employee helpline meant for problems like this. The call is usually entirely confidential, and you might even be able to schedule phone sessions with a counselor.
        \n\n<b>Financial or credit counselor</b>
        \nIf you are worried about finances, talking to someone about money matters can help. A financial counselor might also be able to advise you on how to make the most of your salary.
        \n\n<b>Human resources</b>
        \nYour human resources department is there to help you with situations that seem insurmountable. They can guide you to the proper resources and possibly help you with internal issues.
        \n\n<b>Fitness center</b>
        \nDoes your workplace offer a fitness center? Take advantage of it during your lunch breaks or right before or after work to burn off some steam.
        \n\n<b>Whistle-blower hotline</b>
        \nWhen there are serious indiscretions, illegal activity and the like happening in the workplace, becoming a whistleblower might be your best bet to a better work environment.
        \n\n<b>Fellow co-workers</b>
        \nIf you are in a stressful work environment, how are your coworkers dealing with it? They might be able to provide you with tips on how they stay calm and cool.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_10_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="stress_11_title">5 Health Conditions/Issues Stress Busting Tips</string>
    <string name="stress_11_body">
        When stress becomes overwhelming, it\’s time to
        calm down. These tips can help you deal with health conditions or medical issues without blowing your top.
        \n<b>GET ALL THE INFORMATION YOU CAN.</b>
        \nKnowledge is power, and it can help you cope. The more you know about your condition and treatments, the more in-control you will feel.
        \n\n<b>ENLIST HELP.</b>
        \nWhen you are faced with a debilitating medical condition, you cannot handle it alone. Recognize that you need help, and don’t hesitate to reach out for it.
        \n\n<b>HAVE A GOOD CRY.</b>
        \nTrying to stay strong in the face of a serious
        medical condition might help at first, but over time the lack of \“falling apart\” can
        take a toll. You deserve the time to grieve the situation you are in; allow yourself to cry, scream, rant, and otherwise take out the stress before it makes you even sicker.
        \n\n<b>MAKE PLANS.</b>
        \nIf your medical condition will be a temporary one, consider it a wake-up call, and start planning the rest of your life accordingly. If you are facing a terminal illness, make plans for the time you have left.
        \n\n<b>FIND A SPIRITUAL ADVISOR.</b>
        \nEven if you are not a religious or spiritual person, finding someone who can talk to you about “what comes after” might be a helpful step to put your illness in perspective.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_11_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="stress_12_title">Get help for health-related stress</string>
    <string name="stress_12_body">
            <b>Social workers</b>
        \nEvery hospital or healthcare facility has a social worker on staff, or is able to reach out to one within a short period of time. The social worker can help you find resources such as support groups or financial assistance.
        \n\n<b>Respite care</b>
        \nThose who are taking care of a loved one can turn to respite care, a service often provided by members of the local community. This allows caregivers to take time away from the responsibility and reduce their stress level.
        \n\n<b>Financial department</b>
        \nContacting the billing and financial department can result in payment plans, the potential for lowered payments and other financial assistance.
        \n\n<b>Support groups</b>
        \nTalking to those who are going through the same issues can help alleviate stress. Support groups are available for almost everything, and not just for patients – they are good for children, caregivers, parents and more.
        \n\n<b>Physicians and nurses</b>
        \nThose who work in the health care field can direct you to community resources that can help with everything from getting the right medical equipment to introducing you to new physicians.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_12_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="stress_13_title">Resources and Tools for Stress Management</string>
    <string name="stress_13_body">
        Each person has different types of stressors. What bothers one person might not bother
        another. What seems overwhelming to one might be perfectly manageable to another. But when it comes to your particular kind of stress, you know when you feel it – and you know when it’s becoming serious.
        \n\nThese stress reduction techniques can help anyone, no matter the situation. Whether you
        are in a hospital bed awaiting surgery, dealing with a boss who seems to be out to get
        you, or lonely at college while you await that next test that has you so anxious you can barely study, these tips can ease the worry you are dealing with and help you face the next hurdle with a more centered, calm mind.
        \n\n<b>Relaxation Techniques and Tools</b>
        \n Our expert Melissa Cohen, LCSW, has a few tips that can help ease stress. These are
        her best options for anyone facing a stressful time, including college students, parents, employees, and more.
        \n
        \n1. Acknowledge your feelings and keep a journal – not a formal one but one where you can
        keep notes and thoughts.
        \n2. Prioritize and tackle the easiest things first. This makes the list shorter.
        \n3. Break it down into pieces. Set realistic and manageable goals.
        \n4. Breathe, deeply.
        \n5. Take a break and focus on something else for a while.
        \n6. Do something that you enjoy – draw, write a letter, cook, or call a friend
        \n7. Workout – go for a run, a walk, or take an exercise class
        \n8. Meditate – just 3-5 minutes can help change your perspective
        \n9. Think positive, reframe the negative.
        \n10. Visualize a place where you feel calm.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_13_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="stress_14_title">Avoiding Stress</string>
    <string name="stress_14_body">
        Wouldn\’t it be nice to avoid stress?
        Fortunately, there are some ways you can make that happen. Though there is no way to completely avoid stress, there are some ways to get a better handle on the things that cause it, how you respond to it, and what it does to you. These techniques can help you avoid stress.
        \n<b>KNOW YOUR LIMITATIONS</b>
        \nJumping into something you can’t handle can often
        leave you with stress and worry. When embarking on something new, know what your limitations are, and never bite off more than you can chew.
        \n\n<b>HAVE A GOOD SUPPORT SYSTEM</b>
        \nWhen life gets tough, having someone to turn to
        can help. Your support system should include family, friends, and professionals if necessary.
        \n\n<b>UNDERSTAND YOUR TRIGGERS</b>
        \nWhat stresses you out? Learning to avoid things
        that make you anxious, nervous or worried can be enough to help you live a life filled with less stress.
        \n\n<b>LEARN RELAXATION TECHNIQUES</b>
        \nWhen stress comes calling, being able to relax
        can help you cope with it. Take the time to learn the techniques that make most sense to you.
        \n\n<b>MANAGE YOUR TIME</b>
        \nPlan out your time wisely. This includes any
        situation, including school, career, or everyday life. Make sure to plan in plenty of downtime, too.
        \n\n<b>LEARN TO SAY NO</b>
        \nWhen you say yes to everything, you eventually
        become overwhelmed. Make “no” a strong part your vocabulary, and only say yes to things that will be enjoyable for you.
        \n\n<b>EXERCISE</b>
        \nGetting active releases hormones that can help
        you relax, stay calm and cope with life’s stressors. Even a small amount of exercise each day can work wonders.
        \n\n<b>BE MORE ASSERTIVE</b>
        \nLearn to stand up for yourself and those around
        you. Never allow yourself to be bullied, whether it’s by fellow students, coworkers, a boss or anyone else.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_14_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="stress_15_title">Stress Don\'ts</string>
    <string name="stress_15_body">
        There are very few absolutely certain things in
        life. But when it comes to stress, there are a few things that are simply destined to cause it. These stressors are serious for anyone who deals with them, and they can lead down a road that brings the worst stress you can imagine. If you are dealing with any of these issues, getting help right away – right now – is the only appropriate response.
        \n<b>SUBSTANCE ABUSE</b>
        \nThough turning to drugs and alcohol might seem to relieve stress in the short term, it
        is a recipe for disaster. The negative problems that quickly result will turn your future into a nightmare.
        \n\n<b>ADDICTION</b>
        \nAny sort of addiction can quickly spiral into
        something you can’t handle. Avoid anything that might seem to be an addictive trigger for you, including substances, gambling, and the like.
        \n\n<b>ABUSE OF ANY KIND</b>
        \nIf you are being abused by anyone, in any way,
        get help right now before it gets worse. Emotional, verbal, physical, sexual abuse – as well as other types – can send your stress levels off the charts.
        \n\n<b>ISOLATION</b>
        \nWhen you are feeling isolated for whatever
        reason, stress builds up to the breaking point. If you are suffering alone, without a support group or support system to help you, it’s time to reach out. It might be tough, but there are people just like you who can benefit from the discussions you could have.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_15_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp;BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
    <string name="stress_16_title">Good Stress/Bad Stress</string>
    <string name="stress_16_body">
        Remember that not all stress is bad for you. Sometimes it’s a very good thing. Stress can push you to succeed in areas that you believed were off-limits to you. It can propel you to do things that turn out to be great adventures. It can spur you to study harder, work longer hours, focus more on the things that matter, and take your good health into your own hands.
        \n\nStress can also have a very clear-cut purpose if you are ever in a dangerous
        situation. The “fight or flight” response is a very important biological urge that is designed to lead us out of harm’s way. For instance, the urge to run when someone begins chasing you, or the instinctual need to fight back when you are confronted with a dangerous situation are both a result of this stress response. In that way, stress is a good thing, because it keeps you safe.
        \n\nHealthy stress might make you feel anxious or worried for a time. Imagine the stress
        you feel when taking that big test, the one that your final grade is riding on. The stress might be tough, but it spurs you to study more, and that can drive you to a higher grade. Or imagine the worry you feel when you are struggling with a relationship issue. The worry doesn’t feel good, but it leads you to talk things through more often, and that can lead to a better place in the relationship than what you experienced before the stress took hold.
        \n\nSo before you discount stress as being a terrible thing, think of times when it
        spurred you on to greater things. It might help you put stress in perspective the next time you feel overwhelmed by it.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_16_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS
        AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from
        https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>
</resources>