<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="stress_01_title">What is stress?</string>
    <string name="stress_01_body">Stress is the body’s reaction to a challenge. Though stress is often perceived as bad, it can actually be good in some respects. The right kind of stress can sharpen the mind and reflexes. It might be able to help the body perform better, or help you escape a dangerous situation. Stress produces a physiological reaction in your body. Hormones are released, which results in physical manifestations of stress. These can include slowed digestion, shaking, tunnel vision, accelerated breathing and heart rate, dilation of pupils and flushed skin. This process is often referred to as the “fight or flight” response. That is just what it sounds like: Our bodies are poised to either run away from the stressor or stick around and fight against it.</string>
    <string name="stress_01_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>

    <string name="stress_02_title">Ways of defining stress</string>
    <string name="stress_02_body">
        <b>A stimulus-based definition</b>
\n
The first definition suggests that stress results from pressure. The greater the pressure the more likely that the recipient, whether a person or a load-bearing beam, will succumb. When the (external) stimulus becomes too great, (internal) collapse becomes inevitable. This definition focuses on external sources of stress and encapsulates well its cumulative nature. Adding one more ounce to the weight on the beam may make little difference to the total load but may yet be enough to cause it to break. This is the main definition still provided in the Oxford English Dictionary: \"to subject (a material thing, a bodily organ, a mental faculty) to stress or strain; to overwork, fatigue."
\n\n
        <b>A response-based definition</b>
\n
The second definition focuses on stress as a response to noxious or aversive stimuli. This is the aspect of stress emphasized by Selye (1956), who measured stress in terms of physiological responses, such as those represented by sympathetic adrenal-medullary activity or by pituitary-adrenal-cortical activity. Selye observed what he called the general adaptation syndrome (GAS) during which the physiological response to stress progresses through three stages. First, the body is alerted and responds with an alarm reaction. Next, autonomic activity is triggered as the body prepares to deal with the stress. This is the stage of resistance. Finally, if the stress continues beyond the capacity of the body to respond, the system is damaged and may collapse. This is the stage of exhaustion.
\n
This definition has contributed greatly to the thinking about stress, and it is commonly assumed that psychological responses follow a similar course, although the processes may have an insidious as well as an alarm-based onset. The duration of the stage of resistance, when the person is adapting to, or coping with, the stress depends on specific characteristics of the person suffering the stress, but the assumption is that at some stage, if the stress persists, exhaustion or collapse becomes inevitable.\n
\n\n
        <b>Stress as a dynamic process</b>
\n
Purely stimulus or response-based definitions of stress have thus both contributed to understanding of the phenomenon but they both have limitations. Definitions of stress with more value in clinical practice now emphasize that stress is a dynamic process reflecting both internal and external factors: characteristics of a person and his or her circumstances, as well as the interactionsbetween them. These newer views of stress come from greater understanding of the part played by cognitive factors (thoughts, attitudes, beliefs, images) in psychological well-being. The amount of stress experienced by individuals is determined by the perceived demands upon them as well as by their perceived resources. Cognitive factors thus influence both the stimulus and the response sides of the equation.
\n
Lazarus and Folkman\'s (1984) definition of stress reflects very clearly this way of thinking. They say that stress is "a particular relationship between the person and the environment that is appraised by the person as taxing or exceeding his or her resources and endangering his or her well-being". Two implications of this definition have greatly influenced current thinking about stress and therefore should be made explicit.
\n\n
<b>Implications of a dynamic, cognitive definition of stress</b>
\n
The first implication is that there will be wide differences between people both in the things that are perceived as stressful and in the perception of their ability to respond appropriately. This may mean that the best judge of someone\'s level of stress is the person themselves. An organized, rigid business man may find that adapting to a flexible, unstructured environment taxes his resources to the limit even though his job seems to others not to be particularly demanding. Or conversely someone who regards stress as a psychological weakness to which he or she is invulnerable may misinterpret or ignore signs of stress and need others to point them out. If a housewife with young children supposes that she should be able to respond to each of the small demands made on her (sorting out washing, deciding what to eat, fetching and carrying from school), she will be dismayed to find that an additional task such as taking clothes to the cleaners feels like the last straw. But the appraisals: "nothing I do is particularly difficult" and "anyone should be able to find time for something so trivial" reveal that she may have underestimated the total size of her load, or given insufficient weight to certain types of stressors.
\n
Thinking in terms of appraisals broadens the focus of the clinician. It clarifies how someone who apparently has too little to do may yet feel stressed. An elderly person, or someone who is unemployed, may be subject to few (external) demands but yet have to make demanding internal readjustments. The range of stress stimuli, or possible stressors, is thus greatly expanded. Feelings that cause distress can be stressors as much as the things that provoke them (frustration, jealousy, boredom). The reaction to feeling stressed can provoke more stress, as when someone thinks that showing stress is a sign of failure or weakness. Prolonged, or chronic uncertainty, especially about major life changes, is particularly stressful (threats of redundancy, or the possibility of serious illness), but less so if it is expected and considered (appraised) as normal (waiting for GCSE or A level results).
\n
The second implication of the definition is that stress is determined by the relative balance between two types of appraisal: perceived demands and perceived resources. If the resources outweigh the demands then the person may feel relatively un-taxed. If the person is \'in balance\' then he or she should be operating at maximum eminency. Distress, or suffering, arises when perceived demands outweigh perceived resources. \'Coping\' is the mechanism that potentially provides a degree of control over the balance, and will therefore be considered next.</string>
    <string name="stress_02_cite">Butler, G. (1993, August). Definitions of stress. Retrieved from https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2560943/</string>

    <string name="stress_03_title">Three Types of Stress</string>
    <string name="stress_03_body">
According to the American Psychological Association, there are three types of stress: acute, episodic acute and chronic.
\n\n
        \n<b>Acute stress</b>
\nAcute stress is the most common form and is the result of recent or anticipated stressors. Acute stress can be both positive and negative. For example, the excitement before a fun event is a type of positive acute stress. Getting into a car accident is negative acute stress. As long as the acute stress doesn\’t last for extended periods or occur too frequently, there is nothing wrong with suffering from acute stress. It happens to all of us, and it passes with time.
\n\n
        \n<b>Episodic acute</b>
\nEpisodic acute stress is acute stress that occurs frequently. This is the kind of stress that continuously pops up, sometimes in a pattern. It is accompanied by worry and angst about things that are happening to you or around you. You might be especially prone to this is you have a \”type A\” personality, as you can have a sense of urgency and a need to get things done that might actually become overwhelming. Episodic acute stress is a recurring type of stress, happening over and over.
\n\n
        \n<b>Chronic acute stress</b>
\nChronic acute stress can be thought of as never-ending stress that relentlessly wears away at you. If you don\’t see an end in sight, if you are facing something that has no way out, then you are likely to begin suffering from chronic stress. This type of stress eventually begins to affect your health, and can lead to heart problems, strokes, or even cancer, among other issues. Chronic stress definitely requires reaching out for help.
    </string>
    <string name="stress_03_cite">nCohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>

    <string name="stress_04_title">Causes of Stress</string>
    <string name="stress_04_body">The situations and pressures that cause stress are known as stressors. We usually think of stressors as being negative, such as an exhausting work schedule or a rocky relationship. However, anything that puts high demands on you can be stressful. This includes positive events such as getting married, buying a house, going to college, or receiving a promotion.
\n
Of course, not all stress is caused by external factors. Stress can also be internal or self-generated, when you worry excessively about something that may or may not happen, or have irrational, pessimistic thoughts about life.
\n
Finally, what causes stress depends, at least in part, on your perception of it. Something that\’s stressful to you may not faze someone else; they may even enjoy it. While some of us are terrified of getting up in front of people to perform or speak, for example, others live for the spotlight. Where one person thrives under pressure and performs best in the face of a tight deadline, another will shut down when work demands escalate. And while you may enjoy helping to care for your elderly parents, your siblings may find the demands of caretaking overwhelming and stressful.
\n\n
Common external causes of stress include:
\n &#8226; \tMajor life changes
\n &#8226; \tWork or school
\n &#8226; \tRelationship difficulties
\n &#8226; \tFinancial problems
\n &#8226; \tBeing too busy
\n &#8226; \tChildren and family
\n\n
Common internal causes of stress include:
\n &#8226; \tPessimism
\n &#8226; \tInability to accept uncertainty
\n &#8226; \tRigid thinking, lack of flexibility
\n &#8226; \tNegative self-talk
\n &#8226; \tUnrealistic expectations / perfectionism
\n &#8226; \tAll-or-nothing attitude
\n\n
<b>Top 10 Stressful Life Events</b>
\nAccording to the widely validated Holmes and Rahe Stress Scale, these are the top ten stressful life events for adults that can contribute to illness:
\n1.\tDeath of a spouse
\n2.\tDivorce
\n3.\tMarriage separation
\n4.\tImprisonment
\n5.\tDeath of a close family member
\n6.\tInjury or illness
\n7.\tMarriage
\n8.\tJob loss
\n9.\tMarriage reconciliation
\n10.\tRetirement
    </string>
    <string name="stress_04_cite">Segal, J., Smith, M., Segal, R., and Robinson, L. (November 2018). Stress Symptoms, Signs, and Causes. Retrieved from https://www.helpguide.org/articles/stress/stress-symptoms-signs-and-causes.htm</string>

    <string name="stress_05_title">Symptoms and Signs</string>
    <string name="stress_05_body"><b>Disclaimer</b>
\nThere are four primary types of symptoms of stress: physical, emotional, cognitive and behavioral. Depending on the individual and the cause of the stress, the number of symptoms from each category can vary. The chart below will give an overview to the types of symptoms that may be present in someone suffering from stress.
\n
\n<b>Physical Symptoms</b>
•	\nIrregular bowel movements
•	\nInvoluntary twitching or shaking
•	\nIrregular or missed periods
•	\nGetting sick more often than normal
•	\nReduced libido
•	\nChest pain with or without tachycardia
•	\nHeadaches
•	\nNausea
•	\nMuscle aches
•	\nTrouble sleeping
•	\nHeartburn or indigestion
•	\nFatigue
•	\nFlushed skin
•	\nClenched teeth
•	\nUnusual changes in weight
\n
\n<b>Emotional Symptoms</b>
•	\nLess than normal patience
•	\nFeelings of sadness and/or depression
•	\nFeelings of being overwhelmed
•	\nRestlessness
•	\nReduced or eliminated desire for activities once enjoyed or regularly done
•	\nIrritability
•	\nSense of isolation
•	\nTrouble coping with life\’s issues
•	\nMore frequent or extreme pessimistic attitude
\n
\n<b>Cognitive Symptoms</b>
•	\nImpaired concentration
•	\nTrouble with remembering things, such as homework assignments or deadlines
•	\nChronic worrying
•	\nAnxious thoughts or feelings
•	\nReduced or impaired judgment
•	\nImpaired speech (mumbling or stuttering)
•	\nRepetitive or unwanted thoughts
\n
\n<b>Behavioral Symptoms</b>
•	\nChange in eating habits
•	\nChange in sleeping habits
•	\nNew or increased use of drugs, tobacco or drugs
•	\nNail biting
•	\nPacing
•	\nAbnormal failure or delay to complete everyday responsibilities
•	\nSignificant change in school or work performance
•	\nUnusual desire for social isolation
•	\nFrequent lying
•	\nTrouble getting along with peers, such as coworkers, classmates or teachers
</string>
    <string name="stress_05_cite">Cohen, M. (n.d.). STUDENT GUIDE TO SURVIVING STRESS AND ANXIETY IN COLLEGE &amp; BEYOND. Retrieved from https://www.learnpsychology.org/student-stress-anxiety-guide/?fbclid=IwAR2PRAdPxqHgnUdkWwZI6Z1Uv3dLgsEcClN19gcqhrL9pPC_94cC2vQSUVM</string>

</resources>