<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="depression_01_title">Stress and Depression</string>
    <string name="depression_01_body">
        Stress is good if it motivates you but it\'s bad
        if it wears you down. Many factors can contribute to the stress you experience, and this stress can cause changes in your body that affect your overall physical, mental, and emotional health.
Depression is more serious and long-lasting than stress, and requires a different kind of help. In a 2010 survey by the American College Health Association, 28&#x0025; of college students reported feeling so depressed at some point they had trouble functioning, and 8&#x0025; sought treatment for depression.
How do you tell the difference between stress and depression? Both can affect you in similar ways, but there are key differences. Symptoms of depression can be much more intense. They last at least two weeks. Depression causes powerful mood changes, such as painful sadness and despair. You may feel exhausted and unable to act.

        \n\n<b><font size="14">Common Signs of Stress :</font></b>
        \n<b>•</b>	Trouble sleeping
        \n<b>•</b>	Feeling overwhelmed
        \n<b>•</b>	Problems with memory
        \n<b>•</b>	Problems concentrating
        \n<b>•</b>	Change in eating habits
        \n<b>•</b>	Feeling nervous or anxious
        \n<b>•</b>	Feeling angry, irritable or easily frustrated
        \n<b>•</b>	Feeling burned out from studying or schoolwork
        \n<b>•</b>	Feeling that you can\'t overcome difficulties in your life
        \n<b>•</b>	Trouble functioning in class or in your personal life
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Common Signs of Depression :</font></b>
        \n<b>•</b>	Withdrawing from other people
        \n<b>•</b>	Feeling sad and hopeless
        \n<b>•</b>	Lack of energy, enthusiasm and motivation
        \n<b>•</b>	Trouble making decisions
        \n<b>•</b>	Being restless, agitated and irritable
        \n<b>•</b>	Eating more or less than usual
        \n<b>•</b>	Sleeping more or less than usual
        \n<b>•</b>	Trouble concentrating
        \n<b>•</b>	Trouble with memory
        \n<b>•</b>	Feeling bad about yourself or feeling guilty
        \n<b>•</b>	Anger and rage
        \n<b>•</b>	Feeling that you can\'t overcome difficulties in your life
        \n<b>•</b>	Trouble functioning in your class or in your personal life
        \n<b>•</b>	Thoughts of suicide
    </string>
    <string name="depression_01_cite">REFERENCE : © Copyright Mental Health America 2019</string>
    <string name="depression_02_title">GETTING HELP FOR DEPRESSION</string>
    <string name="depression_02_body">
        \"Depression is not a sign of weakness. Seeking help is a sign of strength.\"
        \nBy just looking at the signs and symptoms of depression and conducting a self-assessment
        will not help you determine whether you have it or not. The best way to find out if you have a depression is to consult a doctor or a professional health care provider who specializes in diagnosing and treating mental health conditions. Know it from the experts who have better knowledge in it. You will take a test or screening to help you assess yourself. Your doctor may perform a physical exam and ask questions about your health. There are no lab tests that doctors provide to specifically diagnose depression. However, your doctor may also require you to take some lab tests to examine out other conditions.
        \n\nTo get started, you can go to your counselling service in your school or the nearest
        mental health center in your community. Most of them provide limited free mental health services and can take you to local providers for longer-term treatment.
        \n\n<b>\"Remember, depression and other mental health conditions are nothing to be ashamed
        of.
        Telling someone you are struggling is the first step toward feeling better. You will need
        the help of a mental health professional to beat depression. Talk therapy, antidepressant
            medication or a combination can be very effective.\”</b>
    </string>
    <string name="depression_03_title">Four things that everyone should know about
        depression:</string>
    <string name="depression_03_body">
        <b>Depression is a real illness.</b>
        \n<b>Depression affects people in different ways.</b>
        \n<b>Depression is treatable.</b>
        \n<b>If you have depression, you are not alone.</b>

        \n\n<b><font size="14">Signs and Symptoms</font></b>
        \n\nSadness is only a small part of depression. Some people with depression may not feel
        sadness at
        all. Depression has many other symptoms, including physical ones. If you have been experiencing any of the following signs and symptoms for at least 2 weeks, you may be suffering from depression:
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Persistent sad, anxious, or \“empty\” mood
        \n<b>•</b>	Feelings of hopelessness, pessimism
        \n<b>•</b>	Feelings of guilt, worthlessness, helplessness
        \n<b>•</b>	Loss of interest or pleasure in hobbies and activities
        \n<b>•</b>	Decreased energy, fatigue, being \“slowed down\”
        \n<b>•</b>	Difficulty concentrating, remembering, making decisions
        \n<b>•</b>	Difficulty sleeping, early-morning awakening, or oversleeping
        \n<b>•</b>	Appetite and/or weight changes
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Symptoms and Diagnosis</font></b>
        \nSymptoms of depression vary widely but can be divided into <b>three main categories:</b>
        \n\n<b>Emotional and cognitive (thinking) symptoms</b> include a depressed mood, lack of
        interest or
        motivation in things you typically enjoy, problems making decisions, irritability, excessive worrying, memory problems and excessive guilt.
        \n\n<b>Physical symptoms</b> include fatigue, sleep problems (such as waking too early, problems
        falling or staying asleep, sleeping too much), changes in appetite, weight loss or gain, aches and pains, headaches, heart palpitations, and burning or tingling sensations.
        \n\n<b>Behavioral symptoms</b> include crying uncontrollably, having angry outbursts,
        withdrawing from friends and family, becoming a workaholic, abusing alcohol or drugs,
        cutting or otherwise hurting yourself, and, in the worst cases, considering or attempting suicide.
    </string>
    <string name="depression_03_cite">REFERENCE: National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH). (n.d.) Depression: What You Need To Know. Retrieved from https://www.nimh.nih.gov/health/publications/depression-what-you-need-to-know/index.shtml
        \nJohns Hopkins Medicine. (n.d.). Depression: What You Need to Know as You Age. Retrieved
        from: https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/healthy_aging/diseases_and_conditions/depression-what-you-need-to-know-as-you-age</string>
    <string name="depression_04_title">Types of Depression</string>
    <string name="depression_04_body">
        These are the several types of depressive disorders.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Major depression:</font></b> Severe symptoms that interfere with the
        ability to work, sleep, study, eat, and enjoy life. An episode can occur only once in a
        person’s lifetime, but more often, a person has several episodes.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Persistent depressive disorder:</font></b> A depressed mood that
        lasts for at least 2 years. A person diagnosed with persistent depressive disorder may
        have episodes of major depression along with periods of less severe symptoms, but symptoms must last for 2 years.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Some forms of depression are slightly different, or they may develop
        under unique circumstances. They include:</font></b>
        \n<b>•	Psychotic depression,</b> which occurs when a person has severe depression plus
        some form of psychosis, such as having disturbing false beliefs or a break with reality (delusions), or hearing or seeing upsetting things that others cannot hear or see (hallucinations).
        \n<b>•	Postpartum depression,</b> which is much more serious than the “baby blues” that
        many women experience after giving birth, when hormonal and physical changes and the new responsibility of caring for a newborn can be overwhelming. It is estimated that 10 to 15 percent of women experience postpartum depression after giving birth.
        \n<b>•	Seasonal affective disorder (SAD),</b> which is characterized by the onset
        of depression during the winter months, when there is less natural sunlight. The depression generally lifts during spring and summer. SAD may be effectively treated with light therapy, but nearly half of those with SAD do not get better with light therapy alone. Antidepressant medication and psychotherapy can reduce SAD symptoms, either alone or in combination with light therapy.
        \n<b>•	Bipolar disorder</b> is different from depression. The reason it is included in
        this list is because someone with bipolar disorder experiences episodes of extreme low moods (depression). But a person with bipolar disorder also experiences extreme high moods (called “mania”).
    </string>
    <string name="depression_04_cite">REFERENCE: National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH). (n.d.) Depression: What You Need To Know. Retrieved from https://www.nimh.nih.gov/health/publications/depression-what-you-need-to-know/index.shtml</string>
    <string name="depression_05_title">Depression affects people in different ways.</string>
    <string name="depression_05_body">
        Not everyone who is depressed experiences every symptom. Some people experience only a few symptoms. Some people have many. The severity and frequency of symptoms, and how long they last, will vary depending on the individual and his or her particular illness. Symptoms may also vary depending on the stage of the illness.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Women</font></b>
        \nWomen with depression typically have symptoms of sadness, worthlessness, and guilt.
        \nDepression is more common among women than among men. Biological, lifecycle, hormonal, and
        psychosocial factors that are unique to women may be linked to their higher depression rate. For example, women are especially vulnerable to developing postpartum depression after giving birth, when hormonal and physical changes and the new responsibility of caring for a newborn can be overwhelming.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Men</font></b>
        \nMen often experience depression differently than women. While women with depression are more
        likely to have feelings of sadness, worthlessness, and excessive guilt, men are more likely to be very tired, irritable, lose interest in once-pleasurable activities, and have difficulty sleeping.
        \nMen may turn to alcohol or drugs when they are depressed. They also may become frustrated,
        discouraged, irritable, angry, and sometimes abusive. Some men may throw themselves into their work to avoid talking about their depression with family or friends, or behave recklessly. And although more women attempt suicide, many more men die by suicide in the United States.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Children</font></b>
        \nBefore puberty, girls and boys are equally likely to develop depression. A child with depression
        may pretend to be sick, refuse to go to school, cling to a parent, or worry that a parent
        may die. Because normal behaviors vary from one childhood stage to another, it can be
        difficult to tell whether a child is just going through a temporary \“phase\” or is
        suffering from depression. Sometimes the parents become worried about how the child\’s
        behavior has changed, or a teacher mentions that \“your child doesn’t seem to be
        himself.\” In such a case, if a visit to the child\’s pediatrician rules out physical
        symptoms, the doctor will probably suggest that the child be evaluated, preferably by a mental health professional who specializes in the treatment of children. Most chronic mood disorders, such as depression, begin as high levels of anxiety in children.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Teenagers</font></b>
        \nThe teen years can be tough. Teens are forming an identity apart from their parents,
        grappling with gender issues and emerging sexuality, and making independent decisions for the first time in their lives. Occasional bad moods are to be expected, but depression is different.
        \nOlder children and teens with depression may sulk, get into trouble at school, be negative and
        irritable, and feel misunderstood. If you’re unsure if an adolescent in your life is
        depressed or just \“being a teenager,\” consider how long the symptoms have been present,
        how severe they are, and how different the teen is acting from his or her usual self. Teens with depression may also have other disorders such as anxiety, eating disorders, or substance abuse. They may also be at higher risk for suicide.
    </string>
    <string name="depression_05_cite">REFERENCE: National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH). (n.d.) Depression: What You Need To Know. Retrieved from https://www.nimh.nih.gov/health/publications/depression-what-you-need-to-know/index.shtml</string>
    <string name="depression_06_title">Causes and Risk Factors</string>
    <string name="depression_06_body">
        Depression is not a mood you can just get over. It is a disease in which the brain ceases to register pleasurable activities, says Angelino. Indeed, MRI studies with depressed people have found changes in the parts of the brain that play a significant role in depression.
        \n\nOther risks for depression include factors such as these:
        \n<b>•</b>	Experiencing stressful events in your life, such as losing your job, having
        problems in your marriage, major health problems, and/or financial challenges.
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Having a bad childhood, such as one involving abuse, poor relationships
        with your parents, and/or your parents own marital problems.
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Certain personality traits, such as getting extremely upset when you’re stressed
        \n\n<b>•</b>	A family history of depression, which can increase your own risk three or four
        times.
        \n\nDepression is far more common than you might think, with nearly one out of 10
        adults depressed at any time, about half of them severely.
    </string>
    <string name="depression_06_cite">REFERENCE: Johns Hopkins Medicine. (n.d.). Depression: What You Need to Know as You Age. Retrieved from: https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/healthy_aging/diseases_and_conditions/depression-what-you-need-to-know-as-you-age</string>
    <string name="depression_07_title">Effect of Depression on Men, Women, and
        Children</string>
    <string name="depression_07_body">
        Depression can be more than a constant state of sadness or feeling “blue.” Major depression can cause a variety of symptoms. Some affect your mood, and others affect your body. Symptoms may also be ongoing or come and go. Depression can affect men, women, and children differently.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Symptoms of depression in men may include:</font></b>
        \n<b>•</b>	Mood: anger, aggressiveness, irritability, anxiousness, restlessness
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Emotional: feeling empty, sad, hopeless
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Behavioral: loss of interest, no longer finding pleasure in favorite activities, feeling tired easily, thoughts of suicide, drinking excessively, using drugs, engaging in high-risk activities
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Sexual: reduced sexual desire, lack of sexual performance
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Cognitive: inability to concentrate, difficulty completing tasks, delayed responses during conversations
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Sleep: insomnia, restless sleep, excessive sleepiness, not sleeping through the night
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Physical: fatigue, pains, headache, digestive problems
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Symptoms of depression in women may include:</font></b>
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Mood: irritability
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Emotional: feeling sad or empty, anxious or hopeless
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Behavioral: loss of interest in activities, withdrawing from social engagements, thoughts of suicide
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Cognitive: thinking or talking more slowly
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Sleep: difficulty sleeping through the night, waking early, sleeping too much
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Physical: decreased energy, greater fatigue, changes in appetite, weight changes, aches, pain, headaches, increased cramps
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Symptoms of depression in children may include:</font></b>
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Mood: irritability, anger, mood swings, crying
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Emotional: feelings of incompetence (e.g. “I can’t do anything right”) or despair, crying, intense sadness
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Behavioral: getting into trouble at school or refusing to go to school, avoiding friends or siblings, thoughts of death or suicide
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Cognitive: difficulty concentrating, decline in school performance, changes in grades
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Sleep: difficulty sleeping or sleeping too much
        \n\n<b>•</b>	Physical: loss of energy, digestive problems, changes in appetite, weight loss or gain
        \n\nThe symptoms can extend beyond your mind. These eight physical symptoms of depression
        prove that depression isn’t just all in your head.
    </string>
    <string name="depression_07_cite"> REFERENCE: V. Higuera &amp; K. Holland. (6 December 2018). Everything You Want to Know About
        Depression. Retrieved from https://www.healthline.com/health/depression#causes</string>
    <string name="depression_08_title">Causes of Depression</string>
    <string name="depression_08_body">
        There are several possible causes of depression. They can range from biological to circumstantial.
        \n\n<b><font size="16">Common causes include:</font></b>
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Family history</font></b>
        \n\nYou’re at a higher risk for developing depression if you have a family history of depression or
        another mood disorder.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Early childhood trauma</font></b>
        \n\nSome events impact the way that body reacts to fear and stressful situations.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Brain structure</font></b>
        \n\nThere’s a greater risk for depression if the frontal lobe of your brain is less active.
        However, scientists don’t know if this happens before or after the onset of depressive symptoms.
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Medical conditions</font></b>
        \n\nCertain conditions may put you at higher risk, such as chronic illness, insomnia,
        chronic pain, or attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD).
        \n\n<b><font size="14">Drug use</font></b>
        \n\nA history of drug or alcohol misuse can impact your risk.
    </string>
    <string name="depression_08_cite">V. Higuera &amp; K. Holland. (6 December 2018).
        Everything You Want to Know About Depression. Retrieved from https://www.healthline.com/health/depression#causes</string>
</resources>